module.exports = {

"Historical Events":

[
  {
    question: "Google was born this year.",
    questionES: "Google nació este año.",
    choices: [
      "1997",
      "1998",
      "1992",
      "1993",
    ],
    answer: "1998",
    note: '',
    time: 10,
    lock: false
  }
  ,
  {
    question: "In 1997, the first of seven books debuted, spawning a new universe.",
    questionES: "En 1997, debutó el primero de siete libros, generando un nuevo universo.",
    choices: [
      "A Series of Unfortunate Events",
      "Goosebumps",
      "Harry Potter",
      "The Magic School bus",
    ],
    answer: "Harry Potter",
    note: '',
    time: 10,
    lock: false
  }
  ,
  {
    question: "The Hubble Telescope is launched into space in this year",
    questionES: "El Telescopio Hubble es lanzado al espacio en este año",
    choices: [
      "1990",
      "1993",
      "1994",
      "1992",
    ],
    answer: "1990",
    note: '',
    time: 10,
    lock: false
  }
  ,
  {
    question: "In 1994, who became the first President of South Africa after being elected in the country's first multi-racial elections?",
    questionES: "En 1994, ¿quién se convirtió en el primer presidente de Sudáfrica después de ser elegido en las primeras elecciones multirraciales del país?",
    choices: [
      "Thabo Mbeke",
      "Nelson Mandela",
      "Fredrik Willem de Klerk",
      "P. W. Botha",
    ],
    answer: "Nelson Mandela",
    note: '',
    time: 10,
    lock: false
  }
  ,
  {
    question: "The Internet becomes available for unrestricted commercial use this year.",
    questionES: "Internet estará disponible para uso comercial sin restricciones este año.",
    choices: [
      "1997",
      "1999",
      "1994",
      "1991",
    ],
    answer: "1991",
    note: '',
    time: 10,
    lock: false
  }
  ,
  {
    question: "Who performed at the 1993 Superbowl?",
    questionES: "¿Quién actuó en el Superbowl de 1993?",
    choices: [
      "Gloria Estefan",
      "Diana Ross",
      "Michael Jackson",
      "Boyz II Men",
    ],
    answer: "Michael Jackson",
    note: '',
    time: 10,
    lock: false
  }
  ,
  {
    question: "OJ Simpson was involved in a high speed pursuit this year.",
    questionES: "OJ Simpson estuvo involucrado en una persecución a alta velocidad este año.",
    choices: [
      '1994',
      '1995',
      '1993',
      '1996',
    ],
    answer: '1994',
    note: '',
    time: 10,
    lock: false
  }
  ,
  {
    question: "Name the location of the 1992 Olympics",
    questionES: "Nombra la ubicación de los Juegos Olímpicos de 1992",
    choices: [
      "Athens, Greece",
      "Barcelona, Spain",
      "Rome, Italy",
      "Atlanta GA, USA",
    ],
    answer: "Barcelona, Spain",
    note: '',
    time: 10,
    lock: false
  }
  ,
  {
    question: "Name the 2 sets of years that Michael Jordan and the Chicago Bulls \"3-peated\"",
    questionES: "Nombra los 2 conjuntos de años que Michael Jordan y los Chicago Bulls \"3-peated\"",
    choices: [
      "1987-1990, 1993-1995",
      "1990-1992, 1994-1996",
      "1994-1996, 1999-2002",
      "1992-1994, 1996-1998",
    ],
    answer: "1992-1994, 1996-1998",
    note: '',
    time: 10,
    lock: false
  }
  ,

],

"TV Shows" : [
  {
    question: "There were two lead characters in this 90's cartoon... one was a genius, the other insane",
    questionES: "Había dos personajes principales en esta caricatura de los 90... uno era un genio, el otro loco",
    choices: [
      "Animaniacs",
      "Ren and Stimpy",
      "The Wild Thornberries",
      "The Powerpuff Girls",
    ],
    answer: "Ren and Stimpy",
    note: "",
    time: 10,
    lock: false
  }
  ,
  {
    question: "Name the song Carlton from Fresh Prince would dance to",
    questionES: "Nombra la canción que bailaría Carlton de Fresh Prince",
    choices: [
      "Livin for the City by Stevie Wonder",
      "Let’s Stay Together by Al Green",
      "It's Not Unusual by Gordon Mills and Les Reed",
      "The Love You Save by The Jackson 5"
    ],
    answer: "It's Not Unusual by Gordon Mills and Les Reed",
    note: "",
    time: 10,
    lock: false
  }
  ,
  {
    question: "When entering the Urkel Transformation Chamber, Steve Urkel would transform into this alter ego",
    questionES: "Al entrar en la Cámara de Transformación de Urkel, Steve Urkel se transformaría en este alter ego",
    choices: [
      "Stefan Urquelle",
      "Stephen Urkel",
      "Stephanie Urkel",
      "Steve Rogers"
    ],
    answer: "Stefan Urquelle",
    note: "",
    time: 10,
    lock: false
  }
  ,
  {
    question: "How many seasons of Seinfeld were there?",
    questionES: "¿Cuántas temporadas de Seinfeld hubo?",
    choices: [
      "10",
      "6",
      "8",
      "9",
    ],
    answer: "9",
    note: "",
    time: 10,
    lock: false
  }
  ,
  {
    question: "Name the extra ingredient Professor Utonium added to create the PowerPuff Girls",
    questionES: "Nombra el ingrediente adicional que el profesor Utonium agregó para crear las Chicas Superpoderosas",
    choices: [
      "Bacteria X",
      "Chemical X",
      "Chemical Y",
      "Bacteria Y"
    ],
    answer: "Chemical X",
    note: "",
    time: 10,
    lock: false
  }
  ,
  {
    question: "In Friends, which character hates Thanksgiving?",
    questionES: "En Friends, ¿qué personaje odia el Día de Acción de Gracias?",
    choices: [
      "Joey",
      "Ross",
      "Chandler",
      "Phoebe",
    ],
    answer: "Chandler",
    note: "",
    time: 10,
    lock: false
  }
  ,
  {
    question: "What is the high school that the students attend in Saved by the Bell?",
    questionES: "¿Cuál es la escuela secundaria a la que asisten los estudiantes en Salvados por la campana?",
    choices: [
      "Bellevue High School",
      "Belleville High School",
      "Bayside High School",
      "Bayview High School",
    ],
    answer: "Bayside High School",
    note: "",
    time: 10,
    lock: false
  }
  ,
  {
    question: "In which fictional city is Buffy the Vampire Slayer located?",
    questionES: "¿En qué ciudad ficticia se encuentra Buffy, la cazavampiros?",
    choices: [
      "Nightingale",
      "Sunnydale",
      "Sunnyview",
      "Tombstone",
    ],
    answer: "Sunnydale",
    note: "",
    time: 10,
    lock: false
  }
  ,
  {
    question: "Which 90’s cartoon character’s catchphrase is \"Eat my shorts\"?",
    questionES: "¿Qué eslogan de un personaje de dibujos animados de los 90 es \"Cómete mis pantalones cortos\"?",
    choices: [
      "Bart Simpson",
      "Doug Funnie",
      "Wakko Warner",
      "Arnold Shortman"
    ],
    answer: "Bart Simpson",
    note: "",
    time: 10,
    lock: false
  }
  ,
],

"Movies": [
  {
    question: "James Cameron’s 1997 mega blockbluster hit was the first to reach two billion.",
    questionES: "El megaéxito de James Cameron en 1997 fue el primero en alcanzar los dos mil millones.",
    choices: [
      "Star Wars Episode 1: The Phantom Menace",
      "Independence Day",
      "Jurassic Park",
      "Titanic",
    ],
    answer: "Titanic",
    note: "",
    time: 10,
    lock: false
  }
  ,
  {
    question: "What is the name of the island that Jurassic Park is set in?",
    questionES: "",
    choices: [
      "Skull Island",
      "Isla Nublar",
      "Shutter Island",
      "Isla de Gracia",
    ],
    answer: "Isla Nublar",
    note: "",
    time: 10,
    lock: false
  }
  ,
  {
    question: "What pill did Neo in The Matrix take?",
    questionES: "¿Qué pastilla tomó Neo en The Matrix?",
    choices: [
      "Red Pill",
      "Blue Pill",
    ],
    answer: "Red Pill",
    note: "",
    time: 10,
    lock: false
  }
  ,
  {
    question: "What is the highest grossing animated film of the 90’s?",
    questionES: "¿Cuál es la película de animación más taquillera de los 90?",
    choices: [
      "Space Jam",
      "The Prince of Egypt",
      "The Lion King",
      "Beauty and the Beast",
    ],
    answer: "The Lion King",
    note: "",
    time: 10,
    lock: false
  }
  ,
  {
    question: "Which movie did Robin Williams star in that featured a magical board game?",
    questionES: "¿Qué película protagonizó Robin Williams que presentaba un juego de mesa mágico?",
    choices: [
      "Jumanji",
      "Zathura",
      "Jumanji: The Next Level",
      "Jumanji: Welcome to the Jungle"
    ],
    answer: "Jumanji",
    note: "",
    time: 10,
    lock: false
  }
  ,
  {
    question: "Who was the James Bond of the 90’s?",
    questionES: "¿Quién fue el James Bond de los 90?",
    choices: [
      "Timothy Dalton",
      "Roger Moore",
      "Sean Connery",
      "Pierce Brosnan"
    ],
    answer: "Pierce Brosnan",
    note: "",
    time: 10,
    lock: false
  }
  ,
  {
    question: "Finish this quote: My momma always said...",
    questionES: "Termina esta cita: Mi mamá siempre decía...",
    choices: [
      "...life is like a box of chocolates, you sure never know what you are gonna get.",
      "...life is like a box of chocolates, you never know what you’re gonna get.",
      "...life was like a box of chocolates, you never know what you’re gonna get.",
      "...life was like a box of chocolates, you never do know what you are going to get.",
    ],
    answer: "",
    note: "",
    time: 10,
    lock: false
  }
  ,
  {
    question: "What famous Whitney Houston song is featured in \"The Bodyguard\"?",
    questionES: "¿Qué famosa canción de Whitney Houston aparece en \"The Bodyguard\"?",
    choices: [
      "I Have Nothing",
      "I Will Always Love You",
      "Run To You",
      "I Wanna Dance With Somebody"
    ],
    answer: "I Will Always Love You",
    note: "",
    time: 10,
    lock: false
  }
  ,
  {
    question: "What song is featured in the movie \"Ghost\"?",
    questionES: "¿Qué canción aparece en la película \"Ghost\"?",
    choices: [
      "Unchained Love",
      "Unbridled Love",
      "Unrestrained Melody",
      "Unchained Melody"
    ],
    answer: "Unchained Melody",
    note: "",
    time: 10,
    lock: false
  }
  ,
]


}

